OYINDAMOLA SALAKO

Contact

Email: oyindasalako@yahoo.com Web: https://osalako.github.io/ LinkedIN | GitHub

Summary

Professional experienced in designing enterprise-wide business intelligence solutions to improve key performance metrics, increase productivity, and eliminate inconsistencies.

- Developed solutions to track 700K+ service tickets and \$600M+ annual expense to assist with operational planning for ~150M+ sqft
- Directed National Mentoring Program for 400+ mentees & 100 mentors
- Skilled in Python, SQL, Power BI, Data Visualization and Modeling

Skills

Data

Visualization & Storytelling Statistical Analysis Management Modeling

Tools

SQL Server Management Studio & Analysis Services Power BI & DAX Excel, PowerPoint

Programming & Query

Python R HTML/CSS/JS SQL

Interpersonal

Problem-Solving Collaborative Inquisitive Adaptable

Education



Analytics, Master of Science

Business, Specialization Georgia Institute of Technology | Grad: May 2022

SEATE CONTROL SEATE OF SEATE O

Economics, Bachelor of Arts

Information Systems, Minor California State University Long Beach | Grad: May 2018

Experience

Lead Financial Analyst, Real Estate Analytics & Systems

AT&T | Dallas, TX | Jul 2019 to Present

- Created business intelligence suite of automated reporting to enhance building management strategies and process improvements for Property Management Org
- Improvements: reducing pending tickets by 30% from 40K to 30K, on average while total created tickets reduced by 10K; redefining service level agreements, rebalancing regional area/property manager portfolios
- Utilize ETL and data architectures to provide data/analytics services, build visualizations, and coach self-service analytics

Financial Analyst & Chief of Staff, Finance Development Program

AT&T | Dallas, TX | Jul 2018 to Jul 2019

- Collaborated with various teams across AT&T Communications Company (ACC) to create executive presentations, talking points, and related documents for the Board of Directors, Operations Review, and ad-hoc meetings and conferences
- Designed as an in-house consultant on the automation team to transform financial reports into real-time multi-faceted dashboards in 9 different Xandr business units, providing performance metrics easily accessible to leadership

Finance Intern, Digital Media Finance

Studio71 LP | West Hollywood, CA | Jan 2018 to May 2018

 Analyzed financial data, trends, and opportunities in traditional entertainment and digital media content to support 7 cross-functional teams in Advertising Operations, Talent Management, and Human Resources